<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gumulka.net</title>
    <description>the notepad of ideas</description>
    <link></link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>8 types of wastes in manufacturing</title>
        <description>
          How to spot wasteful activities in your work - 
          Downtime is the consequence of waste It’s also acronym for 8 types of waste as defined by lean management. In IT some kinds of waste is hard to observe and measure as we don’t produce physical objects. Defects How many times client says “It’s not working” or “It’s not what...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 23:01:29 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>/notes/downtime-8wastes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/notes/downtime-8wastes/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fishbowl</title>
        <description>
          
          Fishbowl Goals Deep-dive into selected topic of high importance by group of interest Well defined list of expectations Vision of desired outcome Enabling all participants to voice their opinions over key topics Deepens participants observation skills Participants Group of interest Moderator Scrum Master Prerequisites Before start refresh relevant knowledge among...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 23:01:29 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>/notes/fishbowl/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/notes/fishbowl/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Maieutics - Socratic method</title>
        <description>
          
          gr. μαιευτικός maieutikhos It is named after the classical greek philosopher Socrates and is introduced by him in Plato’s Theaetetus as midwifery (maieutics) because it is employed to bring out definitions implicit in the interlocutors’ beliefs, or to help them further their understanding. 1 It’s not suited for discovering new...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 23:01:29 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>/notes/maieutics/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/notes/maieutics/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Opportunities and challenges</title>
        <description>
          
          Goals Identification Team and new SM both define potential opportunities and challenges ahead Defining clear rules and values from the start of cooperation in new team Team identifies areas they treat as important Fresh start with health attitude Participants The Team Scrum Master Prerequisites Room and items needed Room to...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 23:01:29 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>/notes/opportunities-and-challenges/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/notes/opportunities-and-challenges/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Turning grumble into actions</title>
        <description>
          Turn grumpy cats into agents of change - 
          Being a grupmy cat is not a bad thing, but it’s not very productive either. In this scenario we try to teach our team how to turn their grumbles in constructive way. Team learns how to express their needs in actionable way, so that they can be addressed by involved...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 23:01:29 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>/notes/turning-grumble-into-actions/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/notes/turning-grumble-into-actions/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Teams vision of goal</title>
        <description>
          Defining common goal, and steps to achieve it - 
          In this scenario we try to define a common goal for the team, and steps to achieve it. It’s a good idea to do this exercise at the beginning of a new project, or when team is formed. It’s also a good idea to repeat it from time to time,...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 23:01:29 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>/notes/vision-of-goal/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/notes/vision-of-goal/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Workplace checklist</title>
        <description>
          
          Making workplace better is a never ending process. Having a checklist of different practices and behaviors to take notice of eases the task by providing a starting point in inspect phase of inspect&amp;amp;adapt cycle. It’s not a complete list, but it’s a start. It’s beneficial to create such list as...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 23:01:29 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>/notes/workplace-checklist/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/notes/workplace-checklist/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>You care only about what you measure</title>
        <description>
          
          Measurement is a key part of tracking progress of any kind of work. Well defined and transparent way of measuring, with a goal of improving key areas of focus is a key to success. It’s not enough to just measure, we need to act on the results, of course, but...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 23:01:29 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>/notes/you-dont-care-about-it-if-you-dont-measure-it/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/notes/you-dont-care-about-it-if-you-dont-measure-it/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
